A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1925-1930
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia 1925-1930
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.472 IX
This collection consists of 6,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Scope and Content Information
This collection consists of correspondence and related papers of John Lloyd Newcomb, assistant to the president, who performed the duties of acting president while President Edwin Anderson Alderman was ill.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically.
Contents List
- Assistant to the President--Files 1925-1930
  - "A" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 1)
    Committee on Academic Legislation report; School of Aeronautic Engineering--reasons for location at University of Virginia; Akerman, Alfred; Alumni Board of Trustees; American Association of University Women; American Bankers' Association
  - Aeronautics 1925-1930 (Box 1)
  - Aitken, Robert 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Statue of three American liberators
  - Alderman--Budget Notes 1925-1930 (Box 1)
  - Alderman--Correspondence 1925-1930 (Box 1)
  - Association for Higher Education in Virginia 1925-1930 (Box 1)
  - Athletics 1925-1930 (Box 1)
    Student fees--see also "D" Miscellaneous under "Driver"
  - Automobiles--Regulations 1925-1930 (Box 1)
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, (1 of 2) (Box 1)
    Balz, A. G. A.--re: Philosophy Department, McKelding; Bane, Frank; Barr, Stringfellow--re: Virginia Quarterly Review; Bolling, Albert
  - "B" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, (2 of 2) (Box 2)
    Brown, F. L.--re: Taylor Tower clock, report of Committee of Clocks and Bells; Bryan, John Stewart objects to student publication The Virginia Reel; Buck Gordon to serve as delegate to Constitution Week; office of Business Manager not to be created; Byrd, Harry; Byrd, Richard C.
  - Bear, James A. 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Bills (passage of) 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Biology--Blandy Farm 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Bok, William 1925-1930 (Box 2)
    re: Lanza Estate
  - Budget 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1925-1930 (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Correspondence with Architects 1925-1930, (1-3 of 8) (Box 2)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Correspondence with Architects 1925-1930, (4-8 of 8) (Box 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds--Prospective Buildings 1925-1930 (Box 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds 1925-1930 (Box 4)
    see also: Chandler, Charles L; "L" Miscellaneous--Lambeth
  - Bursar 1925-1930, see: Carruthers, E. I. (Box 4)
  - "C" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 3 folders (Box 4)
    Calendar; Cappon, Lester J.; Carson, W. E. w/ State Commission on Conservation and Development; Carter, C. L. with C and A Railway Co.; Catlett, Charles--re: coordinate women's college; cemetery; Center College presidency; Chaloner bonds; Chase, H. W. of UNC--reformation of University Senate at University of Virginia; Society of Cincinnati; Commission on a Liberal Arts College for Women, Administrative Committees of the Faculty
  - Campbell, Edmund S. 1925-1930 (Box 4)
    Damages to statue loaned to University of Virginia; plan of French Room; gifts
  - Carruthers, E. I. 1925-1930 (Box 4)
  - Chandler, Charles--Superintendent of Buildings and Grounds 1925-1930 (Box 4)
  - Clemons, Harry 1925-1930 (Box 4)
    see also: "L" Miscellaneous--Library
  - Commons 1925-1930 (Box 4)
    Cafeteria; see also: Kincaid
  - "D" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 5)
    Dabney, R. H.; Davidson College; Davis, Arthur Kyle; Dean of Women; Dean's List; Drinking at the University of Virginia; Driver, James T., Athletic Director
  - "E" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 5)
    Early, Sen. Nathaniel B.; Eason, Thomas D., Secretary of State Board of Education; Eckenrode, H. J.; Engineering Department; English-Speaking Union
  - Eddy Foundation 1925-1930 (Box 5)
  - Education 1925-1930 (Box 5)
    see: "M" Miscellaneous--Manahan
  - "F" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 5)
    Faculty; Failures, statistics on; Fain, Sarah Lee; Fellowships; Ferguson, George O.; Fitz-Hugh, Carter H.; Flippin, J.C., Dean of Medicine; Fraternities; Fredericksburg, college at; Freeman, Douglas S.
  - Fees 1925-1930 (Box 5)
  - "G" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 6)
    Gary, Hampson; General Athletic Association; General Education Board; Geological Survey; Gooch, Robert K.
  - Gee, Wilson 1925-1930 (Box 6)
  - Gibboney, Stuart 1925-1930 (Box 6)
    Thomas Jefferson Memorial Foundation
  - "H" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 6)
    Hart, Harris--Superintendent of Public Instruction; Hartfield, Joseph M.; Hetwole, C. J., V. E. A.; House, Floyd N.
  - Hornsby, John A.--Superintendent of University Hospital 1925-1930 (Box 6)
  - Hospital 1925-1930 (Box 6)
  - "I" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 6)
    Indiana University; Insurance, Institute of Public Affairs
  - Institute for Research in the Social Sciences 1925-1930 (Box 6)
    see: Gee, Wilson
  - "J" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 7)
    Jarman, J. L., State Teachers College at Farmville; Johnson, James G., Superintendent of Charlottesville schools; Jordan, J. E., Department of Medicine
  - "K" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 7)
    Kimball, Fiske; Kuper, Theodore F.
  - Kincaid, E. A. 1925-1930 (Box 7)
    the Commons
  - "L" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 7)
    Laird, Walter J., Wilmington Trust Company; Lambeth, W. A.; Lewis, Ivy; Library--see also: Clemons, Harry
  - Laboratory, Chemistry Building 1925-1930 (Box 7)
    Bids for addition
  - "M" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 3 folders (Box 7)
    Macconcochie, A. F.; Manahan, J., Dean of Education Department; Medical Building; Metcalf, J. C., Dean of Graduate School; Mitchell, S. A.
  - McGuire, Murray 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - Malone, Dumas 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - Maphis, Charles G. 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - "N" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 8)
    Nashville Banner; Nelson, Leon M.; Nelson, Wilbur A.; Newcomb, L.M.
  - Nurses' Home 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 8)
    Ohio State University; University of Oklahoma; Omicron Delta Kappa; Owl Society
  - "P" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 8)
    Page, J. M.; Parker, Franklin N. re suicides on American campuses; Peck, Joseph A.; Pemberton, John C. re: creation of Raymond F. Baby Scholarship; Pinchot, Gifford; Pollard, John G.; Pratt, John Lee; Professors, new
  - Perkins, W. Allan 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - Philosophy 1925-1930 (Box 8)
    see "B" Miscellaneous--Balz
  - Post Office 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - Power Plant 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - Publications 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 8)
    Questionnaires
  - "R" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 3 folders (Box 8)
    Randolph, Agnes--re: fund for Nursing School; Red Cross; Registration; Relgion; Reynolds, Bruce D.; Rinehart, Hollis; Robinson, Joe T.; Ryan Thomas F.
  - Rogers, George Floyd 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - "S" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 3 folders (Box 8)
    Sanger, W. T.; Scattergood, J. Henry--re: possibility of Croatan Indian being admitted; Schmidt, correspondence re: furniture for Romance Dept.; Scholarships; University Senate; Seven Society; Schackelford, George S.; Shepley, Henry R.: Sketch of University of Virginia; Slemp, C. Bascom; Student Self-Help; Sullivan, George H.--re: gifts in memory of Algernon Sydney Sullivan; Swanson, Claude A.
  - Salaries 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - Scott Family 1925-1930 (Box 8)
    re: Gifts
  - Sociology 1925-1930 (Box 8)
    See "H" Miscellaneous--House
  - Summer Session 1925-1930 (Box 8)
  - "T" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 10)
    Taylor, Robert C.--re: money for Medical Building; TIAA; Tidewater Forwarding and Brokerage re: works of art shipped from Italy; Tiffany bequest; Trinkle, E. Lee
  - Tilton, McLane 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 10)
    Alumni Association
  - Tunstall, Robert B. 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - "U" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 11)
    United Artists Corporation; United States Government; University Hour
  - "V" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 11)
    Virginia Engineering Co.; Virginia Quarterly Review; see also "B" Miscellaneous under 'Barr'; Virginia Trust Company; Vyssotsky, A.
  - Virginia Conference on Higher Education 1925-1930, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Virginia Conference on Higher Education 1925-1930 (Box 11)
    Lists of Graduates
  - Virginia Conference on Higher Education 1925-1930 (Box 11)
    Statistics and questionnaires
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1925-1930, (1 of 2) (Box 11)
  - Virginia State Chamber of Commerce 1925-1930, (2 of 2) (Box 12)
  - "W" Miscellaneous 1925-1930, 3 folders (Box 12)
    Walker, Clifford, re: bronze tablets; Wallerstein, Morton L.--League of Virginia Municipalities; Webb, R. H.; Wilkins, Ernest H. of Oberlin College, re: Honor among college students; Williams, Lewis C.; Wranek, W. H.
  - White, Williams H. 1925-1930 (Box 12)
    Foundation
  - Wilmington Trust Co. 1925-1930 (Box 12)
  - Women's Trust Co. 1925-1930 (Box 12)
  - "X-Y-Z" Miscellaneous 1925-1930 (Box 12)
    Yancey, H. A., City Manager of Charlottesville; Young, G. B., Health Officer; Zaffre, Dr. Fred C.
  - Zehmer, George B. 1925-1930 (Box 12)
    Division of Extension